Doctor Who: The Next Doctor is a science fiction, tv
movie, mystery film directed by Andy Goddard.
The Doctor arrives in Victorian London.
It's Christmas, but snow isn't the only thing descending on the tranquil and jubilant
civilization, as familiar silver giants from an alternate reality are amassing in numbers.
The Cybermen are on the move again, and the only beings
who can stop them are the Doctor and...
another Doctor?
The Doctor, played by David Tennant.
Jackson Lake, played by David Morrissey.
Miss Hartigan, played by Dervla Kirwan.
Rosita, played by Velile Tshabalala.
Cybershade, played by Ruari Mears.
Cyberleader, played by Paul Kasey.
Doctor Who, also referred to as Doctor Who: The Movie or as Doctor Who: The Television Movie or Dr Who in the US
is a 1996 television film continuing the British science fiction television series Doctor Who.
Developed as a co-production between Universal Studios and BBC Worldwide, it premiered on 12 May 1996 on the Canadian television station CITV in Edmonton,
Alberta, Canada, 15 days before its first showing in the United Kingdom on BBC One and two days before being broadcast in the United States on Fox.
It was theatrically released in some countries.
The first attempt to revive Doctor Who following its suspension in 1989, it was
intended as a backdoor pilot for a new American-produced Who TV series.
It introduced Paul McGann as the Eighth Doctor in his only televised appearance as the character until "The Night
of the Doctor" in 2013 (though McGann has portrayed the Doctor also in various audio productions).
It also marks the final appearance of Sylvester McCoy as the Seventh Doctor until his cameo appearance in "The Power of the Doctor" in 2022, the only appearance of Daphne Ashbrook as companion
Grace Holloway, and the only onscreen appearance of Eric Roberts's version of The Master, although he has since reprised the role in audio dramas for Big Finish Productions.
Although a ratings success in the United Kingdom, the film did not fare
well on American television and no series was commissioned.
The series was later relaunched on the BBC in 2005.
The only Doctor Who episodes between the film and the new series were a 1999 spoof, Doctor
Who and the Curse of Fatal Death, and a 2003 animation, Scream of the Shalka.
Although primarily produced by different entities than the 1963–1989 series and intended for an American audience, the producers
chose not to produce a "re-imagining" or "reboot" of the series but rather a continuation of the original narrative.
The production was filmed in Vancouver, British Columbia and is the
only episode of Doctor Who to be filmed in Canada.
The film explores themes of cyborg, time travel,
alien, christmas, christmas special.
The tone is thought_provoking and mind_bending.